<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Work in Progress | Christian Roerig</title>
    <link>/research/</link>
      <atom:link href="/research/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Work in Progress</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© 2021</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>/img/avatar.jpg</url>
      <title>Work in Progress</title>
      <link>/research/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>An example conference paper</title>
      <link>/research_project/first_year_chapter/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/research_project/first_year_chapter/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-note&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
    Click the &lt;em&gt;Cite&lt;/em&gt; button above to demo the feature to enable visitors to import publication metadata into their reference management software.
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-note&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
    Click the &lt;em&gt;Slides&lt;/em&gt; button above to demo Academic&amp;rsquo;s Markdown slides feature.
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Supplementary notes can be added here, including 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://sourcethemes.com/academic/docs/writing-markdown-latex/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;code and math&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Monetary policy with oligopolistic competition, firm heterogeneity and entry</title>
      <link>/research_project/first_year_chapter-copy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/research_project/first_year_chapter-copy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The standard textbook New Keynesian model relies on counter-cyclical profits for monetary policy to
have an effect as recently pointed out by Broer et al. (2018). This paper first tests this hypothesis by
adding oligopolistic competition and static free entry to an otherwise standard NK model. Including
search and matching frictions to the labour market, breaks the result of money neutrality despite
free entry of firms. Beyond that, the model is further augmented to accommodate firm heterogeneity
and dynamic entry to investigate how the market structure affects the propagation of monetary policy
shocks. The findings are threefold: First, through the channel of oligopolistic competition, heterogeneity
in firms&amp;rsquo; productivity leads to pro-cyclical profits for lower levels of wage rigidity compared to the
homogeneous case. Second, firm heterogeneity increases the response in aggregate output which is in
line with Mongey (2017). Third, dynamic entry is further enhancing this effect, yet the strengthening
of competition has a negative impact on firms&amp;rsquo; profits. Local projections using Compustat firm-level
data and Romer and Romer (2004) monetary policy shocks support the predictions of the theoretical
model.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
